(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-24T12:30:50.753119",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
What's up!
I am Chaos, the end of and...
I still rose trapped in the cage of ice, your best friend, Bae!
From hololive English Promise!
Witness me!
Yesss! Happy 5 years, everyone!
Koneko, yabakunai?su ne, minna yabai su ne, koneko.
Thank you so much for joining me today for my fifth anniversary stream.
I can't believe it's been five years. We're also in a very nostalgic place.
Yakkoku mo ne, chotto natsukashii basho ni kimashita yone?
Ah, this is the stage from my 3D debut stream, and I thought it'd be fitting to return back here for my big fifth.
Yes, back in the fun zone, back in the fun zone.
We're going to be hanging out with some awesome guests.
I can't believe some of the guests that are very graciously agreed to appear today.
Uh, maybe some games, maybe some singing, and that's not all.
As you may or may not already know, huge announcements with an S.
Are coming your way, so make sure you stick to the very end.
Eto, makyu desu ne? Goshuunen oiwai.
To iu koto nan de, etto,ゲストさん も、あの、すごい、ゲストさんが来てくれてますので、本当,
自分も信じられないぐらい、えっと、楽しみにしています。
Chotto, gēmu yattari toka, mā, uta mo ne, chotto, aru ka na? Chotto wakannai kedo. Ato, chūdai happyō mo takusan arimasu no de, saigo made mite tte kudasai.
And please make sure to share your thoughts on the stream using hashtag Bae Big Fifth.
Bae Big Fifth. I'll be checking all your posts after the stream, so don't
Let's get to pi!
AtlasNet!
#BaeBig5th
Without further ado,
let's jump right into our first segment!
Let's go!
BAE-GEMITE
Celebrate! Celebrate!
Happy 5th anniversary, Bae!
Aye! Aye!
私？
Me?!
Okay, okay!
Mori Calliope from Hololive English -Myth-!
And also best friend! My best friend!
Best friend!
Who's this?
Oozora Subaru, Hololive JP 2nd Generation!
And...
Best friend?
Wait, wait, wait!
You said, "I'm your best friend, Bae's takos."
So you're not my best friend, you're her best friend!
Mr. Friend! Mr. Friend!
Mr. Friend!
Ninomae Ina'nis from Hololive English -Myth-!
I also want to be Bae's...
Best friend!
Tokoyami Towa from Hololive JP 4th Generation!
Yes!
Bae's number one best friend!
All my best friends are here!
And we're the number one best friends!
I will fight you!
BAE-GEMITE
It's my 5th anniversary!
Bae-gemite Extravaganza, Part 1!
Welcome to Bae-gemite...
Wait!
Here comes Bae-gemite again!
You love Bae-gemite way too much!
Bae-gemite is the best!
BAE-GEMITE. It's inspired by the greatest food of all...
Vegemite!
Packed with vitamin B,
it truly is the ultimate spread.
In fact, it wouldn't be an exaggeration to say that...
everyone in my country grew up eating it.
And today, I'd like all of my guests to experience the true greatness of Vegemite firsthand.
Today, we have a very special rendition of...
Bae-gemite!
Okay!
Bae-gemite Showdown!
We're gonna play a game, okay?
We're gonna play a game, and whoever loses...
will discover that they might be missing something, you know?
Do you know what it is?
Calli?
Do you have any idea what they could be missing if they lose?
Yeah, that's right. Nutrition!
Yay!
なるほどね
I see.
ってことです
That's right.
Are you ready?
I'm ready!
Ready, ready, are you ready? Are you ready?
I guess we're ready!
The stage of trials, manifest yourselves, Fun Zone!
Let the stage trials begin—manifest yourselves, Fun Zone!
え、待って、待って！
Wait, wait, wait!
すごい！何これ！
Whoa! What is this?!
I don't know you could do that. That's crazy!
I didn't know you could do that! That's crazy!
急にでてきてるよ、そう。
It just suddenly popped out, yeah.
バエの巣からです、おっ？これか。すっごい。
It's straight from Bae's nest! Oh, is this it? Whoa!
The game we're playing today is the ultimate tricycle race! Tricycle, tricycle!
3、2、1、です。ってことでね。
3, 2, 1, go! That's right.
え？
Eh?
The rules are very simple. We'll all ride a tricycle and complete two laps around the course we've set up here in the Fun Zone...
And the challenge is to see if you can beat my time.
ええ！
Whoa!
ええ？待て待て、オッケーオッケー。
Eh? Wait, wait, okay, okay.
そう、出さなくていいってことね。
Ah, so we don't have to put it out, right?
あ、ま、うん。お互い、お互い、まあ、一応さ、うん、そうですね。
Ah, well, yeah. Both of us, well, sort of, yeah, that's right.
If you win, if you win, if you win, if you win...
ということで、ちょっと早速始めたいと思いますが、準備いいですか？
With that said, we'd like to get started right away. Are you ready?
オッケー！じゃあ、先輩お二人...
Okay! Then, the two seniors...
お二人？俺が勝つと思います！
The two of you? I think I'm gonna win!
ガマントワは？
What about you, Towa?
Tricycle, come on!
これブーン、レディス、レディス、レディス、レディス...
Vroom! Ladies, ladies, ladies, ladies...
オーケー！オーケー！ブーン！オーケー！
Okay! Okay! Vroom! Okay!
オーケー！オーケー！ブーン！オーケー！オーケー！
Okay! Okay! Vroom! Okay! Okay!
圧倒の声量！しかし三輪車との相性は未知数！
Powerful voice! But how will she handle the tricycle?!
器用さは随一！テクニカルな走りに期待！
Top-tier skill! Can she pull off a technical ride?!
ジャンケンしたいです。
I want to rock-paper-scissors.
あ、そう、オッケー。
Ah, right, okay.
どっちが有利なんじゃないかなと...
Wondering which side has the advantage...
Rock paper scissors to find out who gets to ride on the inside.
ロック・ペーパー・シザーズ・シュート！
Rock, paper, scissors, shoot!
うわあ！やったあ！
Whoa! Yay!
イエーイ！
Yay!
ナイス、ナイスです。
Nice, nice job.
じゃあ、常闇側がうちが、いいですね。
So Towa gets the inside track, right?
そういうことですね。じゃあお二人、お二人からちょっと意気込みを...おねがいしていいですか？
That's right. So, can we get some enthusiasm from the two of you?
あ、はい。アイ・ム・ウィーン！
Ah, yes. I'm a ween!
ウィーンさん、ハロウィン、ハロウィン、ね！ウィーンさん、ハロウィン、ハロウィン、ね！ウィーンさんじゃない！
Ween-san, Halloween, Halloween, right! Ween-san, Halloween, Halloween, right! Not Ween-san!
常闇さ、アイ・ム・ウィーン！
Towa-san: "I'm a ween!"
タグって、いてえ！いてえ！
Tagged—ouch! Ouch!
じゃあ、乗ってきなさい。はい。
Now then, get on. Yes.
バエ、バエ、バエ、Yes, this battle.
Bae, Bae, Bae, Yes, this battle.
ブーン、オッケー？ブーン、オッケー？ブーン、オッケー？ブーン、オッケー？
Vroom, okay? Vroom, okay? Vroom, okay? Vroom, okay?
You can interfere with each other if you want. Friendly fire allowed!
But you just can't get off your tricycle. Okay, ちょっと3、2、1降り、降りるのはちょっとダメ。
But you just can't get off your tricycle. Okay, wait, 3, 2, 1, getting off is not allowed.
あ、なるほどね。でも妨害もオッケーです。
Ah, I see. But interference is okay.
妨害オッケー？オッケーです。やばい、ボーン壊れる！
Interference is okay? Okay. Oh no, the bone's gonna break!
じゃあ、いいですか？いくよ！響くよ！
Then, are you ready? Here we go! Let's echo!
ウィーン！3！2！1！ゴー！
Ween! 3! 2! 1! Go!
おめでとうございます！コングラチュレーション！
Congratulations! Congratulations!
アイ・ム・ウィーンさ。アイ・ム・ウィーンさ。
I'm a ween-san. I'm a ween-san.
What technically wasn't just a battle between the nichijou and the taimatakku nan de...
What technically wasn't just a battle between daily life and time attack...
ラップだけじゃない！華麗なライディングにも期待！
More Than Just Rap! Expect a Stylish Ride!
WAHパワー全開！？意外なスピードに期待！
WAH Power?! Unexpected Speed!
All righty, seems like Calli and Ina are all set. Are you two feeling confident?
Oh! ごめんごめんごめん。ちっちゃいね、いなちゃんね。ちっちゃいね。いなちゃん、いなちゃんちっちゃいね。
Oh! Sorry, sorry, sorry. You're so small, Ina-chan. So small. Ina-chan, Ina-chan is so small.
You guys ready? Can we get a  one comment from both of you, please?
You guys ready? Can we get a comment from both of you, please?
私勝つ。勝つ？勝つ？
I'm gonna win. Win? Win?
どん? あ、勝っさ。
Don? Ah, Kassa.
勝つのはどっちだろ
Who's gonna win?
勝つんだ！勝つんだ！
I'm gonna win!
みーさんと、かーさん...
Me-san and Ka-san...
Ina is hungry~
お腹空いた
I'm hungry.
どれぐらいの...勝つぞ
How much... I'm gonna win.
勝つと？カツどん？カツを...
Win? Katsudon? Katsu...
やばい、めでたい！めでたい！
Oh no, congrats! Congrats!
めでたいね！もう全部行くしかねえ！
Congrats! Gotta go all out!
じゃあ、OKですか？
Alright, is that okay?
じゃあ、内側がイナで、外側がコール...
So, inside is Ina, outside is Calli...
外側が明らかに強い、だから、勝ったほうが外側！イエス！
Outside is stronger, so winner gets outside! Yes!
ロック、ペーパー、シザーズ...
Rock, paper, scissors...
シッ！パー！あー！負けた！
Shoot! Paper! Ah! I lost!
I get the feeling Ina's gonna win this one...
いや、ちょっと待って
No, wait a second.
Are you guys ready?
Yeah! ここから、ここから！
Yeah! Here we go!
3！2！1！
Three! Two! One!
GO！
Go!
あ、すっごい！早い！
Ah, wow! Fast!
いけ！いけ！
Go! Go!
早い！早い！
Fast! Fast!
逃げろ！逃げろ！
Run away! Run away!
There will be no one in front of me!
行くぞ！イナ！
Let's go, Ina!
抜け！抜け！誰も私の前を走らせない！
Pass her! Nobody runs in front of me!
早い！早い！
Fast! Fast!
行け！行け！
Go! Go!
足の裏、擦りすぎて痛い
My soles hurt from rubbing too much!
きねっさ！
Roots!
いや！大丈夫じゃないよ！
No! You're not okay!
大丈夫？大丈夫？イナの足が...
Are you okay? Ina's legs...
With the four of them completing the race, I think we should announce their times...
タイムは発表されます！お楽しみに！
Times will be announced! Look forward to it!
じゃあ、最初は...
Now, first is...
すばる先輩！の、タイムは何でしょう！
Subaru-senpai! What will her time be?!
28.85 seconds!
早っ！早くない？これ！
Fast! Isn't that fast?!
早いすね！早い！早くない？これ
That is fast! Isn't that fast?
じゃあ、次はトワ様！
Next is Towa-sama!
タイムは...
Time is...
35.63 seconds!
おっそ！遅い、遅い！
So slow! Slow, slow!
でも、35.63秒ね
Still, 35.63 seconds.
次はカリオペ！Your time is...
Next is Calliope! Your time is...
36.72 seconds!
やった！私ファースト？
Yay! Am I first?
え？早っ、え？何？え？
Huh? Fast, eh? What? Eh?
で、最後はイナ！
And finally, Ina!
Your time is...
38.44 seconds!
え？でもさ、36.72と38.44...
Eh? But, 36.72 to 38.44...
えと、みんな早くね？いやちょっと遅いね
Um, aren't everyone fast? A bit slow, huh?
つまり、ベイちゃん、メイビー君も私たちと同じくらい遅い...
In other words, Bae-chan, maybe you're also a little slow like us...
40秒ぐらいでお願いしたいところが...
I'd like to ask for around 40 seconds...
So, I have to beat みんな食べれる
So, I have to beat everyone's time, if it's
バイだったら、28.89ければいいってことじゃん？
Vegemite... if I beat 28.89, that's fine right?
どこに入るかね、ベグ...
Where will I fit, Veg-
Where with that being said, it's my turn! Let's go!
ベジマイトパワーで驚異のタイムを見せられるか！
Can Vegemite power deliver a blazing fast time?!
ということで、ベの準備ができそう です！やった！
So, Bae's preparation seems ready! Yay!
よーし、いこう！一番に合ってるわ！
Alright, let's go! It fits me best!
ジャストフィット！ジャストフィット！
Just fit! Just fit!
パーフェクトでしょ？
Perfect, right?
普段からだって乗ってるでしょ？乗ってねえよ！
You usually ride it anyway? I don't!
Beruna's bicycle... I know how to ride! どうですか？意気込みをお願いします
Beruna's bicycle... I know how to ride! How is it? Enthusiasm please.
いや、もうすべてはベジマイトのためである。僕は勝つ！
Well, everything is for Vegemite. I will win!
For Vegemite! とんでもないよ
For Vegemite! That's outrageous.
ベジマイトを好きすぎるな、ベジマイト人間だから
You love Vegemite too much, because you're a Vegemite human.
ベジマイトから生まれたんじゃない？だからベ？あ、そういうこと、だからベです...そういうことなんだ、長かったね
Weren't you born from Vegemite? So Bae? Ah, that's why? So Bae... I see, that was a long story.
どうせ勝つだし、大丈夫。めっちゃ感じや
You're gonna win anyway, it's fine. Great vibe.
そんなこと言ったらさ、トワがさ、あ、すみません...ちょっと遠い、戻ってもいいですか？
If you say that, Towa's like, ah, sorry... a bit far, can I go back?
はい、当たりまーす！
Yes, you got it!
ってことで、じゃあ…
So, then...
はい、これでね、順位決まりますから我々。
Right, this will decide our rankings.
我々、ベジマイトと二度どうなるかというのはこれできまりますから！
Whether we will ever touch Vegemite again will be decided by this!
はい！じゃあ、練習ということでいいですか？
Alright! Is practice okay?
ヒュウィー、GO！GO！GO！
Here we go, go, go!
うわ、やばい、やばい、やばい！
Whoa, yikes, yikes, yikes!
なんか、マジ必死！
Like, seriously desperate!
やばい、やばい、ガチのやつ！
Yikes, yikes, for real!
シリアスじゃん、シリアスじゃん！
It's so serious!
うわ、やばい、やばい！
Whoa, yikes, yikes!
あ、危ない、危ない、曲がって、曲がって！
Watch out, turn, turn!
うわ、まっすぐ、まっすぐ、まっすぐ！
Whoa, straight, straight, straight!
でも、早すぎちょっと！
That was way too fast!
早すぎるんだよ！
Way too fast!
でも、楽しかったですけどこれ。
Well, it was fun though.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
じゃあ…
Now then...
発表！行きますか！
Announcement! Shall we go?!
さっきの順番でどこだったっけ？さっきの順番ね。
In the previous order, where was it? The previous order.
ポコナタイムお願いします！
Pokona Time, please!
全員、ベジマイト食べます！
Everyone's eating Vegemite!
お上品ものすぎるマジで！
This is way too classy, seriously!
みんなの心のごちようなんで、もうこれはプレゼントです。
This is everyone's heart's feast, so this is a present.
なんか言ってる。いいように言ってるだけじゃん！
She's saying something nice. She's just spinning it!
なのだ、みんなちょっと待ってね。We're gonna get to the place prepared to taste some Vegemite!
So everyone, wait a moment. We're gonna get to the place prepared to taste some Vegemite!
やっぱね、この4人が入った瞬間に、もう分かってました。
As you know, the moment these four entered, I already knew.
栄養が足りてなーい！
They're lacking nutrition!
なので、こちらをご用意しております。
So, we have prepared this for you.
朝ごはんはいちばん大事な食事なんで、今日は皆様に栄養たっぷり、朝ごはんを用意しております！
Breakfast is the most important meal of the day, so today we have prepared a breakfast full of nutrition for everyone!
ベリシャスなんですか？A very delicious dish, very delicious dish
Very delicious dish, very delicious dish.
では、ちょっと1つずつご紹介させてください。
Now, let us introduce them one by one.
まずですね、あの…生ベジマイトありますね。
First, um... we have raw Vegemite.
えっと、これは後でね、あの…Towa様と…うーん…INAは食べたことないんで、1回ちょっとね、生で食べていただきます。
Um, later... Towa-san and... Ina hasn't tried it, so we'll have them try it raw once.
これはもう健康的な朝ごはんを用意しております。まずはパン、パンにベジマイトを塗って…
This is a healthy breakfast. First, bread... spreading Vegemite on bread...
これはまあ、オーストラリア定番の朝ご飯です。This is a very traditional Australian breakfast
This is a very traditional Australian breakfast.
で、次参ります。味噌汁でございます。まあ…
And next. Miso soup. Well...
When we speak of Japanese breakfast, we think of miso soup. 味噌汁ですね。あの、朝ごはんで言えば、もう本当に豪華！
Miso soup. When we speak of Japanese breakfast, we think of miso soup. Truly luxurious!
朝ごはんといえば、やっぱりお寿司ですね！
When we speak of breakfast, it's definitely sushi!
朝から寿司食わねえよ！And I just need someone to agree with me that Vegemite and sushi is amazing.
Who eats sushi in the morning?! And I just need someone to agree with me that Vegemite and sushi is amazing.
ちょっとね、認めてほしくて、寿司とベジマイトマジで合うんだって！
I want you to admit it, Vegemite and sushi actually go really well together!
どこにつけたの、ベジマイト？ワサビみたいにちょっと裏、ちょっとつけて…
Where did you put the Vegemite? Put it on the back like wasabi...
なので、ちょっとTowa様とINAは、あの、ベジマイト初なんで、ちょっと生で…get rid of the taste of any other food!
So, Towa-san and Ina are trying Vegemite for the first time, so raw... get rid of the taste of any other food!
いただきます！Try it. Try it.
Itadakimasu! Try it. Try it.
え、普通？
Eh? Normal?
めっちゃいい顔してる。
You're making a great face.
まあ、いけなくはない。
Well, it's not terrible.
いけなくはない。
It's not terrible.
なるほどですね。
I see, I see.
いけなくはない。はい、オッケーです。
It's not terrible. Okay, understood.
レッツゴー！
Let's go!
ドンスケアリー！恐れる…
Don't scary! Don't be afraid...
ドンスケアリー！
Don't scary!
いきます！
Here we go!
そんない悪くない。
It's not that bad.
セーフ！あ、さすが！
Safe! Ah, as expected!
そんない悪くない。イコール…
Not that bad equals...
おいしいでしょ？
Delicious, right?
うん、悪くない。
Yeah, not bad.
悪くない！いける！
Not bad! It's good!
じゃあちょっと、みんなの朝ごはんタイム行きますか？
Shall we move on to everyone's breakfast time?
じゃあ最初パンでお願いします。
First up, bread please!
いただきます。
Let's eat.
パンで。
Bread.
いただきます。
Let's eat.
え、おいしいでしょ？
Eh, it's delicious, right?
おいしいですよ、ね。
It's delicious, right?
うん、おいしい！
Mmm, delicious!
んー、んと、トーストだと…
Mmm, wait, with toast...
しょっぱ、しょっぱ！
It's salty, salty!
It is pretty salty.
Yeah, it is pretty salty.
おいしいですよね？
It's delicious, right?
ほら、ほら。全然バツじゃない。
Look, look. It's not bad at all.
ちょっと味が濃い。
Just a bit strong.
味は濃いっすね。まあ、そうですね。
The flavor is strong. Well, that's true.
パン食ったあとにちょっと飲みたくないじゃないですか。
After eating bread, don't you want something to drink?
飲みたい！じゃあ次はお味噌汁お願いします！
I want to drink! Next is miso soup, please!
お味噌汁おいしい！おお！うっ！おいしっ！
Miso soup is delicious! Oh! Wow! Delicious!
ベリーグッド、ベリーグッド！
Very good, very good!
I don't taste it in the...
なんか味が…
But it tastes like...
普通のお味噌汁。
Regular miso soup.
いや、うまいです、おいしいよ。おいしい汁。
No, it's good, it's delicious. Delicious soup.
これ合格です。
This is a pass.
合格？ありがとうございます。
A pass? Thank you very much!
最後ちょっと本当に、
Last one is really...
最後きっつ。いや…
Last one is tough. No...
魚の方でちょっと食べてほしいんですけど。
We'd like you to try the fish version.
いや、これやば！絶対おいしい！
No, this is yikes! Definitely delicious!
いただきます。You don't have to dip it in soy sauce. マグロの… That's not fish!
Let's eat. You don't have to dip it in soy sauce. Tuna... That's not fish!
マグロ！It's salmon!
Tuna! It's salmon!
I want maguro sushi!
醤油につけなくていいの？
Do I not need to dip it in soy sauce?
いや、しょっぱいんで。
No, because it's salty.
どう？いず、こえる？
How is it? Can you get over it?
いただきます。
Let's eat.
ああー！な、びびった…
Aah! Wh-, that startled me...
いや、うまい！いや、違う、違う、違う、違う。おいしい、おいしい。
No, it's good! No, wait, wait, wait, wait. Delicious, delicious.
最初おいしいの顔してた。
At first, you made a delicious face.
Two stars. Two stars. Two stars.
じゃあいただきます。
Well then, let's eat.
そうだよね、分かるよ。ジャッカル！愛しクソとわ…愛しクソだよ。
That's right, I understand. Jackal! Beloved piece of crap... It's a beloved piece of crap.
いや、だからこのベジマイトとタイミング… いやいやいやいや！
No, so this Vegemite and timing... No no no no!
ノーベジマイトじゃない？なんか。ベジマイトなくない？
Isn't it no Vegemite? Somehow. Isn't there no Vegemite?
ベジマイトない。
There is no Vegemite.
There is no Vegemite. え、だからぶっと、おん、おんベジマイト。
There is no Vegemite. Eh, so put it right on, on Vegemite.
中だと思わないんだって。
We wouldn't think it's inside.
ちゃんと付けたほうがいいと思うけど。ダイレクト、ダイレクトベジマイトしないと。
I think you should put it on properly. You have to put Vegemite directly on it.
あ、そうだよね。そっち？
Ah, that's right. That way?
そうそうそうそうそうそう。
Yeah, exactly, exactly.
そうすると星2になるよ。いか！いきます。
If you do that, it becomes two stars. Squid! Here we go.
She's so cute! Why?
でも、いいかな。大丈夫っすよ。
But, I guess it's fine. It's okay.
なに、なにいいですか？ なんか？ お寿司を買って… 冷蔵庫にちょっと入れて…
What, what is it? Something? I bought sushi and put it in the fridge for a bit...
買ったの忘れて
I forgot I bought it...
寿司の日に食べる感じの味がする
It tastes like something you'd eat on a special day.
寿司の日じゃん！寿司の日じゃん！
It's Sushi Day! It's Sushi Day!
寿司やん！いやでもその…
It's sushi! But still...
忘れとったの？
Did you forget?
忘れとったわ、あの、匂いが…
I forgot... Um, the smell...
すし酢が出とる、すし酢が。
Sushi vinegar is coming out, sushi vinegar.
つっこ、美味しいな！
It's super delicious!
ワッツスター、ワッツスター、ちゃめにスター、スリースター
Watts Star, Watts Star, Chamele Star, Three Star
どうせ外れ、How many? How many star?
Probably a miss. How many? How many stars?
5！Five star! Five star, out of five!
5! Five stars! Five stars out of five!
out of 10, out of 10!
10 out of 10! Out of 10!
9 out of 5! 9 out of 5は out of vibe ですよね？
9 out of 5! 9 out of 5 is totally out of vibe, right?
やっしゃあ！
Yay!
僕が食べた時めっちゃ美味しかったんすけど、なんで？
When I ate it, it was super delicious, but why?
ハコス乃トースト is crazy なのかな？
Is Hakos' toast being crazy... possible?
まあ、それはまあ、味ようど、まあ、一旦よしとして…
Well, as for the taste, let's call it good for now...
栄養はたっぷり入ってます！おー！
It's packed with nutrients! Oh!
Yeah, nutritious!
And I think ちょっとね、前に、あの、行きましょうか。
And I think let's move forward a bit.
ちょっと、みんな前に出る。
Everyone step forward a bit.
Thank you for the food. You're welcome!
ごちそうさまでした！美味しかった！
Thank you for the meal! It was delicious!
いやあ、ちょっとね、なんか、道具がいいか、一味違う！一味違う！
Man, the tools make it a cut above! Totally different!
ほらほら、もう栄養、栄養の、の、のせいか。栄養ダンス！
Look, look, is this because of all the nutrients? Nutrient dance!
いや、本当に、楽しかったです！ありがとうございます！Thank you!
Man, it really was fun! Thank you very much! Thank you!
I'm so happy that, oh my you know, lovely friends could join me in best friends, celebrating my 5th anniversary...
I'm so happy that, oh you know, lovely friends could join me as best friends, celebrating my 5th anniversary...
And you know, not only I get to celebrate it with Vegemite, but also with these lovely ladies and also I have a huge announcement!
And you know, not only do I get to celebrate it with Vegemite, but also with these lovely ladies, and I also have a huge announcement!
ちょっと、重大発表が… 重大発表が来てしまった…
A major announcement, a major announcement has arrived...
ビッグニュース、ビッグニュースのやつが来ましたので…
Big news, big news has arrived...
If you're ready, it's time for the huge announcement! Please take a look at this!
What moves thy heart? / 汝の心を動かすものはなんだ？
What moves thy heart?
What is thy true desire? / 真の望みはなんだ？
What is thy true desire?
The fallen crown awaits from the shadows... / 失われた王冠は影の中で待つ
The fallen crown awaits from the shadows...
Her time has come, / 彼女の刻は来た
Her time has come,
No one will ever question her rule again. / 何人もあるその支配を拒むことはできない
No one will ever question her rule again.
2026.12.01 Hakos Baelz 1st Concert
December 1st, 2026 / Hakos Baelz 1st Concert
決めつけばかり 自惚れを纏た / チープなhokoriで 音荒げても
Judging constantly, draped in vanity, raising a voice with cheap pride
棚に隠した 哀れな 羞に濡れた鏡の中
Hidden on the shelf, in the pitiful, shame-drenched mirror
都合の傷だけひび割れさせて 手軽な強さで勝負取る術を
Making only convenient wounds crack, finding easy strength to win
Offer up thy soul and kneel. / 魂を捧げ、そして平伏せ
Offer up thy soul and kneel.
For those who bow before her will... / 彼女の意志に跪く者たちよ...
For those who bow before her will...
WITNESS HER LEGACY! / 彼女の軌跡を目撃せよ
WITNESS HER LEGACY!
ああああああ！
Ahhhhh!
I finally did it! I can't believe it guys!
I did it! I am finally holding my very own...
ソロライブ！ソロライブ決定です！やったー！
Solo live! My solo live is confirmed! Yay!
I'm so happy! いや本当にありがとうございました！
I'm so happy! Man, thank you so much!
It's going to be happening on December 1st of this year, and the venue is none other than Kanadevia Hall in Tokyo!
It's going to be happening on December 1st of this year, and the venue is Kanadevia Hall in Tokyo!
えっと、なんと12月1日決定されました、ソロライブです！東京のカナデビアホールで開催決定です！
Umm, it has been decided for December 1st, a solo live! It's confirmed at Kanadevia Hall!
えっと、ライブのタイトルは「REGALIA」！I chose this title because I wanted this live to be all...
Um, the title of the live is "REGALIA"! I chose this because I wanted this live to become...
a symbol of my journey so far,
and hopefully a symbol for what is yet to come
for a Bae's take cause, you know,
eto, my konkai no live title wa "Regalia" desu.
Um, the title of this live is "REGALIA."
Kono live wa, ne, boku no kore made no katsudou wo shouchou ni suru zo tte iu ishi wo komete kono title ni shimashita.
This live will symbolize everything I've done so far,
Eeto, ticket ya goods no jouhou wa gojitsu happyou shimasu node, mousu sukoshi matte te kudasai.
Ticket and merch info will be announced later on, so please wait a little longer.
Tickets and goods will be announced later on.
Please get hyped!
I did it! I did it!
And there's more!
In celebration of my first ever solo live, I am so happy to announce that my second album, Mirror Mirror, is on its way!
My second album, "Mirror Mirror," is on its way!
Pre-orders will open today from 9:00 PM JST on the Hololive Production Official Shop.
Pre-orders open today at 9:00 PM JST on the Hololive Official Shop.
Soshite, eeto, ma, live ni mukete, second album mo, ano, demasu!
And my second album is also coming out for the live!
Mina-mina tte iu release ga, ano, kettei shimashita!
It's been decided that "Mirror Mirror" will be released!
Eeto, nihon jikan de kyou 23 nichi no yoru 9 ji kara, eeto, hololive production kousiki shop de, ano, de, chuuchuu kaisi saremasu!
Pre-orders start tonight at 9:00 PM Japan time on the official shop.
Arigatou gozaimasu! Hontou ni arigatou gozaimasu!
Thank you so much! Thank you truly!
This album is so special to me.
It includes many songs, actually, I wrote the lyrics of most of the songs on this album,
I wrote the lyrics for most of the songs on this album,
with the theme of reflection, facing oneself, and this album was a project where I pushed myself to explore even more ways to express myself as an artist.
with the theme of reflection and facing oneself as an artist.
Eeto, nanto desu ne, konkai no album no kyoku wa daitai zenbu kashi no hou wa jibun de kaite mashita. Eeto, ma, reflection, jiko tono mukiai tte iu tema no shite, artist to shite no saranae hyougen ryoku wo, eeto, jukyushi tai sakuhin to natte masu.
I wrote almost all the lyrics myself with the theme of reflection.
Ah, it also comes with a lot of album bonuses. You'll receive a special message letter with my signature, an original mirror sticker, and an artbook-style lyric booklet.
It comes with a special message letter, a mirror sticker, and a lyric booklet.
I'll be signing every single one of them,
so please get it!
Atone, album kyuunyu tokuten mo arimasu! Sain-tsuki no special message, nihongo mo eigo mo arimasu. Original mirror sticker mo arimasu. Art book-gata no kasikar mo arimasu. Mou katte kurete kureta minna mo sain-sain wo shimasu node, zehi zehi yoroshiku onegaishimasu.
There are special purchase bonuses, signed letters, and stickers.
You can check the shop directly from YouTube.
And both the album shipments and the digital release are scheduled for November 2nd JST.
Album shipments and digital release are scheduled for November 2nd.
So get hyped, stay tuned, there's a lot yet to come.
Eeto, YouTube kara shop e access dekinu node, zehi check shite kudasai. Mata hassou to digital release wa 11 gatsu 2 ka no yotei de kite orimasu. Tanoshimi ni shite kudasai.
Digital release and physical shipments are coming on November 2nd.
Ah, I may have mentioned before that there is a new song releasing today,
There is a new song releasing today,
and that is right after this stream, the music video for "I found me,"
and that is the music video for "I found me,"
which is a very, very special song that is actually the first song I ever wrote from scratch, will be releasing—will be premiering after this stream.
which is my first song written from scratch, premiering after this stream.
Eeto, kono haishin ga owatta toki ni, chotto, ano, album kara no 1 kyoku "I found me" no MV ga koukai shimasu. Kono kyoku wa boku ni totte metcha daiji na kyoku nande, soshite hajimete 1 kara kaitta kyoku nande, ano kashi no hou ne. Nanode zehi zehi premiere made koukai yoroshiku onegaishimasu!
The MV for "I found me" will premiere right after this stream.
The MV will be the opening video for my segment during YouTube Music Weekend!
The MV will be the opening video for YouTube Music Weekend!
Ta-da! There's a lot! I'm so happy!
My fifth anniversary and I get to be part of YouTube Music Weekend! So it'll be the opening video for my section which starts at 1:15 PM JST, so make sure to check it out.
It's the opening video for my section starting at 1:15 PM JST.
Kono MV wa kono ato 13 ji 15 fun kara start suru YouTube Music Weekend de boku no opening part ni mo natteiru node, zehi zehi kore mo check shite kudasai!
This MV will be the opening for YouTube Music Weekend at 1:15 PM.
Arigatou desu! There's a lot of announcements. Are you guys staying proud of me? I got a silver.
Thank you! There's a lot of announcements. Are you guys proud of me?
You guys know I've been so busy now. I've been busy... I've been already doing a lot of prep
You guys know I've been so busy now, doing a lot of prep
before this amazing event that's happening, and I'll be sharing more details about the concert at a later date. So I really hope you look forward to it.
for this amazing event, and I'll share more details later.
Eeto, ma, saikin chotto boku ne, ano tsukarete iru, plus meccha isogashiku natta riyuu mo kore ni narimasu node, hontou ni ganbarimasu node, ano tanoshimi ni shite kudasai.
I've been tired and busy because of all this, but I'll work hard!
Alright! With that being said, I think it's time to move on to the next segment! Chotto tsugi no corner ni ikitai to omoimasu!
Alright, let's move on to the next segment!
BAE-GEMITE COOK-SHOO-EET! YEAH!
見てる方も、 I think everyone knows but
For those watching, I think everyone knows, but
いつよ？自己紹介お願いしていいですか？
Could you please introduce yourselves?
はい、もちろん でございます。
Yes, of course.
じゃ、私から、え、ホロスターズ2期生の夕刻ロベルです。本日はよろしくお願いいたします！
Starting with me, I'm Yukoku Roberu from Holostars Gen 2. It's great to be here!
ェーイ！
Yay!
なんか不穏な感じがねしますけど。
It gives off a bit of an ominous vibe, though.
そうですね。
That's true.
はい、怖いです。
Yes, I'm scared.
怖くないね。
You're not scared.
怖くないもんね？そうだね。
I'm not scared, right? That's right.
頑張りたいと思います。よろしくおねがいします。
I'll do my best. Thanks for having us.
おねがいします。
Thank you.
はい。あの理由も分からず呼び出されて、仕事だと思って来たらなんだか不穏なスタジオでした。石川界人です。声優です。よろしくお願いします！
I was called here without knowing why, and thinking it was for work, I arrived at this ominous studio. I'm Kaito Ishikawa, a voice actor. Nice to meet you!
よろしくお願いします！
Nice to meet you!
そんな我々からも、ちょっとベエちゃんに言わなきゃいけないことあります。
So from us too, there's something we need to tell Bae.
ありますね。
There is.
じゃあ行きましょう。はい。
Well then, let's go. Right.
せーの！ソロライブ開催決定、おめでとう！
Ready, set! Congratulations on your solo live announcement!
すごいことよ。
That's amazing.
あ、なになにちょっと、お、お、お、うれしい！
Oh, what, what, wait, oh, oh, oh, I'm so happy!
うれしいな。
I'm so glad.
いや、すごいことよ。
Seriously, that's huge.
おめでとう！ありがとうございます！本当に、おめでとう！
Congratulations! Thank you so much! Truly, congratulations!
なんか一VTuberファンとしてさ、
As a fellow VTuber fan,
ソロライブというのは夢じゃん。
having a solo live is the ultimate dream.
夢です！
It's a dream!
夢です、本当に。
It really is a dream.
なんか言ったら...
When you say it like that...
なんかもう熱い、ありがとう！
It's so heartwarming, thank you!
いや本当、本当に素晴らしい。
No really, it's truly wonderful.
えっと、今日はね、チャレンジをやりたいと思います。
Um, today, we'd like to do a challenge.
チャレンジ？
A challenge?
はい。
Yes.
いいですね、挑戦。
Sounds good, a challenge.
今日は、We've invited these two for a challenge called 'The Bae-Gemite Concoctions'. We've come up with some absolutely outrageous Bae-Gemite concoctions.
Today, we've invited these two for a challenge called 'The Bae-Gemite Concoctions'. We've come up with some absolutely outrageous Bae-Gemite concoctions.
ま、ロベルさんとかいとさんはもうベジマイトのことご存じしておりますよね？もちろん。
Now, Roberu-san and Kaito-san are already familiar with Vegemite, right? Of course.
なんか当たり前のように口にしてるけど、そのなんか、そう...
You say it like it's the most natural thing, but...
我々にとっては、その、呪詛みたいなもんかな。
for us, it's kind of like a curse.
怖いのよ、結構。
It's pretty scary.
ベジマイトで言ったらま、ロベルさんですよね？いや結構このもう大御所なんだ。
When it comes to Vegemite, that would be Roberu-san, right? Well, you're practically a veteran at this.
正直この「ベジマイト」という道を作ってしまった発端の人物かもしれない。
Honestly, you might be the person who paved the way for this 'Vegemite' path.
そうです。
That's right.
あの、そうベエちゃんに、そのベジマイトってものがあるよって教えてもらって、僕がその実食配信みたいなのをするようになったんですよ。
Bae told me that there's this thing called Vegemite, and I ended up doing taste-test streams like that.
そこから始まったこの地獄は、多分。
The hell that started from there is probably...
そして被害者、被害者たちが生まれていった。
And then victims, victims started being born.
そうで一緒にね、その配信で、食レポみたいな配信もしたことがあって、
We even did a food reporting stream together back then,
で、それ以来なんで、この、こいつと対峙するのは3、4年ぶりぐらいになりますか、まあ。
and because of that, facing this thing again has been about 3 or 4 years, I guess.
じゃあもう、味も忘れちゃってそうだもんね。
So you must have almost forgotten the taste by now.
あのね、こびり付いてる。4年経っても消えない言い方、味の記憶がこびり付いてる。
Well, it's ingrained. Even after 4 years, it doesn't fade—the memory of the taste is stuck in my brain.
うん、だから非常にね、怖さはあるけど、まあでもね、楽しみですよ。
Yeah, so there's definitely fear, but hey, I'm looking forward to it.
もっと元気そうね。
You seem more energetic.
楽しみです！
I'm looking forward to it!
やーい！
Yay!
すごい楽しみ、食べたい。
Super excited, I want to eat it.
そして界人さん、あの、ベジマイトエピソードっていうことありますか？
And Kaito-san, do you have any Vegemite episodes?
あー、ベジマイトエピソードですか？非常に素晴らしい、あの食材ですよね。
Ah, a Vegemite episode? It's a truly wonderful ingredient, you know.
もらってましたよね？ベエちゃんから。そのホロ声で一緒になったときに、ベエちゃんからありがたいお土産を、
You received some, right? From Bae. When we were together at Holo-koe, Bae gave you a wonderful souvenir,
あんたもらってたよね？
didn't you?
ええ、番組収録終了時ね、わざわざ楽屋にご挨拶いただいて、
Yes, right after the show recording ended, she went out of her way to greet me in the dressing room,
「なんて丁寧な方なんだろう」と「素敵な方だな」っていうふうに思って受け取って、これお土産ですと。
and I thought, "What a polite person" and "What a wonderful person," and I accepted it, saying, "This is a souvenir."
はい。
Right.
ありがとうございます。あれですか？なんか、お菓子か何かですか？あ、ベジマイトです。
Thank you very much. Is that... is it some kind of snack or something? Oh, it's Vegemite.
一応食べましたよ。
I did eat it, you know.
お、えらい！
Oh, impressive!
食べました？
You ate it?
それ偉いですよ。ちゃんと食べました。絶対食べてないと思ったもん。
That's amazing. Iちゃんと ate it. I honestly thought you wouldn't touch it.
なんて素晴らしい食材なんだろうって。
Thinking what a wonderful ingredient it is.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
おめでとうございましたね。
Congratulations on that.
じゃあ、素晴らしいんだやっぱ、ベジマイトっていうのは。
So it really is wonderful, Vegemite.
ベジマイトは素晴らしいです。ちょっとね、記憶もね、あんまないと思いますので、ちょっとさき、生で食べさせてもらいます。
Vegemite is wonderful. But since you probably don't remember much, let's have you taste it raw first.
I gotta refresh their memories on the taste, so we do have Vegemite prepared in front of us.
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
いや、大丈夫じゃないです。
No, I'm not okay.
大丈夫だよ。
It's fine.
あの、お願いってわけじゃなくて、もう、5周年なんで、命令です。食えと。
Look, it's not a request. It's our 5th anniversary, so it's an order. Eat it.
食え。
Eat.
ソロライブも決まるしな。
Your solo live is decided too.
そんなおめでたい人の命令じゃ。そうです。
Coming from such a celebratory person's orders... That's right.
じゃあみんな、あ、怖い！
So everyone... Ah, I'm scared!
はい、じゃあ、せーの！待って、待って！
Okay, ready, set! Wait, wait!
乾杯！
Cheers!
待って、怖い！
Wait, it's scary!
ああー！
Aah!
あ、美味しい。
Ah, delicious.
うまいっ！
Delicious!
すごい！
Amazing!
大丈夫ですか？
Are you okay?
大丈夫じゃな、えっ、もう飲み切っちゃっ、いちゃいました。
I'm not oka— wait, you already finished drinking it!
はい、えー、石川界人 has finished one bottle of water. えーと、早えっすね。
Yes, uh, Kaito Ishikawa has finished one bottle of water. Uh, that was fast.
お水にとっても合うな！
It goes so well with water!
ああー。
Aah.
ああ、しあわせ！
Ah, so happy!
あーー！
Aaah!
大丈夫でしょうか？ ちょっと、あのベンチせいで私の顔がえぐいす…。
Is everything alright? My face looks so wrecked on that bench...
おお…
Oh...
泣いてる。
He's crying.
泣いてます？
Are you crying?
ほぼ泣いてる。
Almost crying.
なん で？
Why?
美味しすぎて。
Because it was too good.
美味しすぎてね、なんだろう、びっくりして泣いてる。
It was so delicious, I don't know, I'm crying from shock.
美味しすぎてね、涙が止まらないね。
It was too delicious, I can't stop crying.
深呼吸して、あの、多分両端死んでる…。
Take a deep breath... probably both ends are dead...
多分両端は死んでると思って。
Thinking both ends were dead.
ああ。
Ah.
まあじゃあ説明行きます。えっと、We have the Vegemite Concoctions!
Well then, let's explain! We have the Vegemite Concoctions!
So it is a tasting might competition, but I mean it's a tasting event!
It's a tasting... might competition—I mean, it's a tasting event!
To explain how it works, before today, Robelu-senpai, Aruran, and I came up with an ingredient that we thought would pair well with Vegemite.
And using all of our ideas—our ideas as inspiration, a professional food coordinator—pro!
And using all of our ideas as inspiration, a professional food coordinator—pro!
A professional food coordinator has created each dish with great care, and we're going to taste all of them and decide who came up with the best Vegemite concoction!
なるほど。我々が選んだ食材でプロの方がすごく美味しくベジマイトを使って料理してくださってると。
I see. So the ingredients we chose were cooked deliciously by a professional using Vegemite.
はい。
Yes.
なるほど。
I see.
ということで、いや、信じられるの？
So, wait, can we really believe this?
いや、しん、え？いやでもベジマイト元々美味しいからね。
Well, wait, Vegemite is originally delicious anyway.
ああ、そうだ。ごめんごめんごめん。シェフプロだからね。
Ah, that's right. Sorry, sorry. Because he's a pro chef.
プロだもんね。
He's a pro, after all.
ベジマイト美味しいしね。
Vegemite is delicious, too.
美味しい。
Delicious.
なので、まあ、美味しいプラス美味しいイコール美味しいじゃないですか。
So, delicious plus delicious equals delicious, right?
ああ、そうですね。
Ah, that's right.
美味しい。
Delicious.
ということで、あの、お互い何選んだか全くわかんない。全く知らないマジで。
So, we have no idea what each other chose. We seriously have no idea.
We don't know what the other has chosen, so it's going to be a surprise to us as well.
まあ、さっそく始めよう。
Well then, let's get started.
あ、なるほど。
Ah, I see.
始めます？
Shall we begin?
いいですよ。始めます？
Sure. Shall we begin?
あの、一端休憩時間欲しいかな？ いや、なんかその中でベジマイトが大暴れしてるんだわ。
Um, can we get a short break first? I feel like Vegemite is going on a rampage in there.
あの、すごいよね。生きてる、これは。
It's amazing, right? It's alive.
まあ、あの、最初ちょっと何を選んだかロベ先輩に聞き、聞いて。
Well, um, first let's ask Robelu-senpai what he chose.
じゃ、僕から行きますか。最初にお願いします。
Shall I go first? Please go ahead.
わかりました。え、では僕が選んだ食材はこちらでございます！
Understood. Well then, the ingredient I chose is right here!
牛タンです！
Gyutan (Beef Tongue)!,
あのね、マジ牛タンです！
Seriously, it's beef tongue!
で、やっぱ、しょっぱいじゃないですか、ベジマイトって。
And after all, Vegemite is salty, right?
で、これはお肉に合うんじゃないかなと思ったんですよ、僕。
And I thought this would go well with meat.
あのね、単純に僕が牛タン食べたかったのもありまして、そのアンケートを書いたときに。
Also, I simply wanted to eat beef tongue when I filled out the survey.
なので今回は牛タンを選ばせていただきました。
So this time I chose beef tongue.
あのね、確かに美味しくならないわけがない。
And you know, there's no way it wouldn't be delicious.
なるほどですね。
I see.
美味しいと思います。
I think it'll be delicious.
確かに焼き肉ケはうまそう。
True, yakiniku style sounds delicious.
ね！牛タン。
Right? Beef tongue.
Gyutan which is beef tongue, it is a yakiniku meat, and the reason he tries it was because, well, it's meat, Vegemite is salty, would be a good pairing. One would think. なるほどね。
Gyutan which is beef tongue, it is a yakiniku meat, and the reason he chose it was because, well, it's meat, Vegemite is salty, it would be a good pairing. One would think. I see.
はい、素晴らしい！
Yes, wonderful!
素晴らしいでしょ、これ。
It's wonderful, right?
これを、ちょっとプロの方にお願いしているので、
We asked a professional to make this, so...
何が出てくるでしょうか！
Let's see what comes out!
ちょっと、ドキドキするなこれ。
Man, this makes me nervous.
じゃ、見ていきましょう！
Well then, let's take a look!
お願いします！
Please!
うまそうだけど！
It looks so good, though!
めちゃめちゃうまそう！
It looks super delicious!
うまっそー！ え、ちょっと待って、ベジマイトを発見できないすよね？
It looks so good! Wait, you can't even spot the Vegemite, right?
ええ、すごい！
Wow, amazing!
どっか入ってる？
Is it hiding somewhere?
これがね、一応、牛タンートルティーヤ。トルティーヤ。ルルティーヤ。 It's like a wrap!
This is, well, Beef Tongue Tortilla. Tortilla. Tortilla. It's like a wrap!
はいはいはいはい。最近はね、タコスも流行ってますから。流行ってますからね。
Right, right, right. Tacos have been trending lately, after all. They're trendy.
で、なんかこの、ソースめちゃいい匂いするっすね。
And like, the sauce smells so good.
ソースをかけたらいいのかな、俺は。
Should I pour the sauce on it, I wonder?
じゃあ、ちょっと食べてみます。
Well then, let's try eating it.
食べてみます。
Let's try it.
ロベルさん、いっちゃってや。ちゃんと！してるな。
Robelu-san, go ahead. You're doing it properly!
いただきます。
Itadakimasu.
ちょっと、ちゃんと、して。
Wait, act proper!
おっ。
Oh.
行ってる、行ってる、行ってる！
He's eating it, he's eating it!
うん。食べてます。
Mhm. He's eating.
じゃあ、僕もいただきます。
Well then, I'll have some too.
お、いい感じだぞ。
Oh, it's looking good.
ロベルさんが、うん、うん、うん。
Robelu-san is like, mhm, mhm, mhm.
ロベルさん、どうよ？
Robelu-san, how is it?
いや、あのね、言っていいっすか？うん。
Well, um, can I say it? Mhm.
全然美味しいっす。
It's genuinely delicious.
えー！
What?!
あの、ベジマイトがどこにいるかかんないです。
Um, I have no idea where the Vegemite is.
え、それ合ってるの？
Huh? Is that right?
わかんないす。
I have no idea.
え、ベーさんも美味い？
Eh, is Bae's delicious too?
うま、うまい。
Delicious, delicious.
うまい！うまいの？そっか、今二人が先に食べてリアクション見てから食べようと思って。
Delicious! Delicious? I see, I wanted to wait and see your reactions before eating.
ありがと。じゃあ大丈夫そうだね。いただきます！
Thanks. Well, seems safe then. Itadakimasu!
こいつ、うーん！うーん！うーん！うまい！
This guy—Mhm! Mhm! Mhm! Delicious!
え？ 本当に、うん。
Eh? Really? Mhm.
ベジマイトがどこにいるかマジでわからん。
I seriously have no idea where the Vegemite is.
で、これ、これはまたプロの方からのあれがあるんですかね？
And this, do we have another comment from the professional?
おお、we have a comment from the food coordinator.
Oh, we have a comment from the food coordinator.
はい、これは、牛タンというのは塩レモンだれでよく食べるところから発想いたしました。
Yes, this was inspired by how beef tongue is often eaten with salted lemon sauce.
レモン塩だれの塩部分をベジマイトにしました。
We replaced the salt part of the lemon salt sauce with Vegemite.
へえー！
Whoa!
The idea came from the way beef tongue is commonly enjoyed with a salted lemon sauce, and instead...
Salt in the lemon sauce we replaced that with Vegemite!
天才すぎだよ！
That's way too genius!
あ、そう？
Oh, really?
なるほど、塩味だけを残したんだ。
I see, you only left the salty flavor.
いやでも、ベジマイトの風味は、あるじゃないですか。
But Vegemite still has its aroma, doesn't it?
あ、でも食べた後ちょっと
Well, but right after you finish eating...
It has like a slight like it's like a refreshing breeze of Vegemite.
なんか優しい風みたいなね。確かにね。うんうんうん。
Like a gentle breeze. That's true. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
ベジマイトが優しい風になることあるんだね。
So Vegemite can turn into a gentle breeze, huh?
そうですね。
That's right.
ベジマイトだけ食べたら岩で殴られたみたいな衝撃あったけど、
If you ate just Vegemite, it hits like getting hit with a boulder,
こんな優しい風に調理できるんだね、ベジマイトってね。
but to cook it into such a gentle breeze, Vegemite...
ベジマイトは優しいです。
Vegemite is gentle.
すごっ。
Amazing!
これは美味しいですね。
This is delicious, huh?
ね。
Right.
では続いて、石川界人さん！
Now moving on to Kaito Ishikawa's!
はい！
Yes!
We're going to move on with Ishikawa Kaito-san's ingredients.
We're going to move on with Kaito Ishikawa's ingredients.
どんなものを選びました？
What kind of thing did you choose?
じゃあ、僕が選んだ食材、こちらです！ドン！
Well, the ingredient I chose is right here! Bam!
なに？
What?
何ですか？
What is it?
納豆です！
Natto!
いやあ！
Whoa!
キタァーー！
Here it comes!
キチッ！キチッ！
Gross! Gross!
あれ、納豆好き？
Wait, you like natto?
納豆好きよ。
I like natto.
ですよね。
Right.
納豆好きよ。
I like natto.
もう癖強には癖強ぶつけたら、こう、なんだろう、ツイスマイツみたいなするんじゃないかなと思って。
If you pit strong quirks against strong quirks, I thought maybe it would create something like a Twismite or something.
I like the way he thinks. I think it's extra-special wonderful.
そう、こちらを選ばせいただきました日本の文化をぶつけてやるぜ！
That's right, we chose this. We're going to clash Japanese culture against it!
This is Japanese culture. Yes.
まあ、without further ado, what is the professional chef going to do this time? 見ていきましょう！おねがいします！
Well, without further ado, what is the professional chef going to do this time? Let's take a look! Please!
どうなっちゃうの、納豆は？
What's going to happen to the natto?
おー！えー！？
Woah! What?!
なんだこれ！どういうこと？どういうこと？どういうことだ？美味そう...
What is this?! What do you mean? What is this? It looks delicious...
どういう、どういうこと？あの発酵生春巻き？
What do you mean? Fermented fresh spring rolls?
発酵生春巻き！生春巻きだ！
Fermented fresh spring rolls! It's fresh spring rolls!
発酵生春巻きって言葉も初めて聞きましたけど、うお、なんかとろとろしてる！
I've never even heard the term "fermented fresh spring rolls," but wow, it looks all gooey!
ほら、もう一口で行くか。いっちゃったよ、ベさん。
Look, are we going in one bite? He went for it, Baelz.
じゃ、ちょっとつけていただきます。
Then, let's dip it a bit and dig in.
うわ、めっちゃ、It's so slimy. いただきます。
Whoa, super—it's so slimy. Let's eat.
え、これ...
Eh, this...
界人さん、え？ 先に言っとく。うん。明確にいる。いる？ いる。
Kaito-san, huh? Let me say this first. Yeah. It's definitely in there. In there? It's in there.
いる！やつがいる。うん？
It's really in there! That guy's in there. Huh?
いるな！いる！いる！
It's really in there! It's in there!
いや、これソースにいるね。
No, it's in the sauce.
ソースか。
The sauce?
うん。
Yeah.
あれ、全然味しないっすけど。え？うまい。
Huh, I don't taste it at all though. Eh? It's good.
え？あれ、チェイスと？ いや、いるよ。え？
Huh? Wait, is it chased? No, it's in there. Eh?
納豆に押し勝ってるぐらいまである。
It's almost overpowering the natto.
相当だね。めっっちゃ美味しい。
That's quite a lot. Super delicious.
うん、美味しい。普通に。発酵同士なので相性がいいということございまして。
Yeah, delicious. Normally, since they're both fermented, they go really well together.
やっぱ、塩味があるので、何かのソースにできるとやっぱ塩味なんすね。
And since it has saltiness, being able to make it into a sauce means it's really all about that saltiness.
納豆のタレ、なるほど納豆のタレをベジマイトにしたらいいなと思い、
Natto sauce—I thought it'd be good to turn natto sauce into Vegemite,
マヨベースにして、その中にベジマイト入りダレを作りました。
making a mayo base and creating a Vegemite-infused sauce inside it.
So Vegemites are really nice and salty. I figured it could work as a base for a sauce. Had the idea of replacing the sauce that comes with natto with Vegemite. Made a mayonnaise-based sauce and mixed Vegemite into it!
うまい！
Delicious!
うまい。食えちゃうんだよね。まあね。食えちゃうはどういうことすか？
Delicious. You can just eat it right up. Well yeah. What do you mean by "eat it right up"?
うまいんだよ。
It's delicious!
納豆、美味しいです。This is so good. Oh my god. もう、キラキラ。へえー。
Natto is delicious. This is so good. Oh my god. So sparkly. Wow.
最後にいきますが、うん、はい。
Finally, we'll move on to—yeah, okay.
食事の、何笑ってんだよお前。何、何、ニヤニヤすんねん。お前。食事の前に普段何食べております？
What are you laughing at, you? Why are you grinning like that? What do you usually eat before a meal?
あ、食事の後？はい。うん、ま、デザートみたいな。デザートですね？
Ah, after the meal? Yes. Yeah, well, like dessert. Dessert, right?
次は僕が選んだ食べ物になります。はい。うん。
Next is the food I chose. Yes. Yeah.
We have reached the final dish. And normally at the end of every meal, you do have dessert. オーストラリア...
We have reached the final dish. And normally at the end of every meal, you do have dessert. Australia...
オーストラリアといえば
Speaking of Australia...
組んだらどうなるか ちょっと
If you combine them, how would it turn out?
宝物２つ？宝物２つを組んだらどうなっちゃうかちょっとめちゃくちゃ、あの、気になったんで、
Two treasures? I got really curious about what would happen if you combined two treasures,
えっと、最後の、あの、材料はこちらになります。何？ こわっ。え？なに？
um, so the final ingredient is right here. What? Scary. Eh? What?
ティムタムです。
It's Tim Tam.
誰？誰？誰？ティムタムは。そのお宝知らないわ。
Who? Who? Who is Tim Tam? I don't know that treasure.
え、ティムタム知らないすか？違うよ、ティムタム。え、
Eh, you don't know Tim Tam? No way, Tim Tam. Eh?
これはオーストラリアのめっっちゃ有名なチョコレート、まあ、あのビスケット、ウエハース？あー、なるほど。あれあれ、ティムタムです。
This is Australia's super famous chocolate, well, like, biscuit, wafer? Ah, I see. That's right, it's Tim Tam.
ティムタムってお菓子ね。お菓子。それをじゃあ
Tim Tam is a snack. A snack. So then—
作れるんだ。その、ベジマイトとかじゃなくて、単体でね。美味しいんだろね。美味しい、ありがとう。
You can make it. Not with Vegemite or anything, just by itself. It must be delicious. Delicious, thank you.
クッキー、ビスケットは。本当に読んでくれてありがと、今日は。ありがとう。このままだよ。
Cookies, biscuits. Thank you so much for reading it today. Thank you. Just like this.
ご褒美だよね、頑張った僕たちに対する。
It's a reward for us working hard.
ということで、ちょっと、あの、プロの方だったから、まあ、あの、ティムタムプラスベジマイト...
With that said, since he's a pro, well, Tim Tam plus Vegemite...
楽しみに... あのまあおいしく... 作ってくれたかなあって
I'm looking forward to it... I wonder if they made something delicious...
んで混ぜんだよ！
Why mix it!
お前作ったんで ああ
Since you made it, ah...
You know It's pressure. I wanted to see what they could do, and I believe in their skills as a pro chef.
見ていきましょう！ お願いします！
Let's take a look! Please!
ええ！？
Eh!?
え！？ え！？ え！？
Eh!? Eh!? Eh!?
おっとおっとおっと！ どういうこと？
Whoa, whoa, whoa! What's this mean?
ティラミス？
Tiramisu?
ティラミスじゃん！
It's tiramisu!
え、うま？ え？ え、おいしそう？
Eh, good? Eh? Eh, looks delicious?
まあ、ちょっと一旦Baeちゃん発案者だしさ
Well, Bae came up with the idea first, so...
そうだよ！先に、そう、食べてみてよ！
That's right! You go ahead and try it first!
はい！いただきます！
Okay! Itadakimasu!
え、でもなんか... え？ カップティラミスめっ ちゃくちゃおいしそう... すごいな！
Eh, but like... Eh? Cup tiramisu looks super delicious... That's amazing!
うわあ！ これがベジマイト入ってる？ いただきます！
Whoa! Does this have Vegemite in it? Itadakimasu!
いやわからん、もう警戒心が強くなりすぎてるだけかもしれん。
I don't know, maybe my guard's just way too high right now.
え、普通に... え、普通にティラミス？
Eh, normally... Eh, normally tiramisu?
いやティラミスじゃん！
Wait, it's tiramisu!
いただきます！
Itadakimasu!
はい。
Yes.
え？ え？ え？ なんか不思議そうな顔してない？
Eh? Eh? Eh? You look kind of confused, don't you?
あれ、本当にに入ってます？ベジマイト。
Wait, is Vegemite really in this?
え？ 入ってそうですよ！
Eh? Sounds like it's in there!
おいしい！
Delicious!
え！？ え！？
Eh!? Eh!?
普通にティラミスやん！
It's just normal tiramisu!
え、普通にティラミス？
Eh, normal tiramisu?
いただきますも...
Itadakimasu also...
いただきますも！ 普通にティラミス！
Itadakimasu too! Normal tiramisu!
あれ？Baeちゃんが一番分かってないまであるからなベジマイト。
Wait, Bae might understand Vegemite the least of all.
ん？
Hm?
マジで、え？ ベジマイトが、いるのか？
Seriously, eh? Is Vegemite actually in here?
かすかに塩味があって、うまっ！ うおお！
There's a faint saltiness, delicious! Whoa!
Oh my god!
え！？ これお店出しましょう！
Eh!? Let's open a shop with this!
はい！ 本当に...
Yes! Really...
本当、We need copyright! Need a patent! Oh my god!
Really, we need copyright! Need a patent! Oh my god!
すごい！ めっちゃうまい！
Amazing! Super delicious!
えー ティムタムと合う料理は思いつくのが大変でした。すみませんでした！ 本当に。
Uhm... It was hard to think of dishes that go well with Tim Tam. I'm so sorry! Truly.
ティムタム自体はコーヒーが相そうと思ったのでティラミスにしました。はい！ ティムタムの
I thought Tim Tam itself would go well with coffee, so I made it tiramisu. Yes! Tim Tam's
クッキーはサクサクおい... 生かしたいので、ティムタムを... 砕いて、ベジマイトを...
cookies are crispy... I wanted to utilize that, so I crushed the Tim Tams and... infused Vegemite...
染み込ませ... 染み込ませ、あ、ティムタムも砕いて、その中にベジマイト入れて、混ぜて、それをやってるんだ。
let it soak... let it soak, ah, crushed Tim Tams, put Vegemite in them, mixed it, and did that.
So hey, apparently it was really hard to think of a dish that will pair well with Tim Tam, but Tim Tam goes well with coffee. Decided to make a tiramisu, also wanted to keep the crunchy texture of the Tim Tam, so I crushed it up, soaked it with Vegemite, so good.
え！？ すごくうまい！
Eh!? So delicious!
しかも普通のティラミスより美味しくなってて
And it's even tastier than regular tiramisu!
でしょ！？
Right!?
塩味が良い味出してる！ そう。
The saltiness brings out a great flavor! Yeah.
甘みが際立つというか。
It highlights the sweetness, you could say.
で、かつなんか生クリームの甘さとかがこの塩味によってちょっと中和されるかともあって、めちゃくちゃクドくない！
And also, the sweetness of the fresh cream gets somewhat neutralized by this saltiness, so it's not overly cloying at all!
ねえ！
Right!
うまい！
Delicious!
うまい！ ティラミスにすることによって、コーヒーの香りと苦みで、そのティムタムのすっごい甘い感じも、程よくまろやかになって
Delicious! By making it tiramisu, the coffee's aroma and bitterness mellow out that super sweet feeling of the Tim Tam just right.
てか、ティムタムがうまいんじゃないの？ これ？ ティムタムうまいんじゃない？
Wait, isn't Tim Tam just good? Isn't Tim Tam good?
でも、ティムタムのおいしさをちょっとね、浄化させたのもうベジマイトのおかげなんで、All because of Vegemite, Tim Tam's deliciousness have been, you know,
Well, Tim Tam's deliciousness was purified thanks to Vegemite. All because of Vegemite, Tim Tam's deliciousness has been, you know,
これうまっ！ すっごいわ！
This is so good! Incredible!
え、プロってすごいな！ あのベジマイトをこんなにできるの？
Eh, pros are amazing! Can you really do that with Vegemite?
あのベジマイトやめてください。
Please stop with that Vegemite.
ごめんなさい。
Sorry.
めっちゃ食ってますね。 よかったです。 完食です。
You're eating a lot. I'm glad. It's finished.
あのね、全部うまかったな。 総じて、今んとこ3個食べたけど、うん。
Well, everything was good. Overall, I've eaten 3 so far, yeah.
ええと、ちょっと最後に、美味しさっていうか、もう三つ星の評価というか、それをやりたくて。
Uhm, finally, I want to rate them like three stars for deliciousness.
I want to rate all of the different dishes.
どれが一番美味しいかつとね、決めたいので。
I want to decide which one is the most delicious.
まあ今まで食べた中でどれが一番ベジマイトと相性が良かったかってことね。なるほど。
Well, among the ones we've eaten so far, which one went best with Vegemite. I see.
じゃあまず、えっと、先輩の牛タンですね。
Then first, uh, Sempai's beef tongue.
な何星ですか？ How many stars are we giving the gyutan?
How many stars? How many stars are we giving the gyutan?
おお。
Oh.
俺は 2つ星かな？
I'd say two stars?
Two stars?
まあ俺も2かな。2になるかな。 いや、僕も2だと思いましたね。いや、めちゃくちゃ美味しかったですよ。
Well, I'd say 2 as well. Might be 2. Yeah, I thought 2 as well. It was really delicious though.
美味しかった。
It was delicious.
次が、はるさん納豆ですね。
Next is, Haru-san's natto.
納豆ね。
Natto, right.
あ、1つ星かな？ ごめん、俺も1つ星かな。
Ah, one star maybe? Sorry, I'm one star too.
え？
Eh?
自分は2.5なんですけど。 あれ？ え？ めちゃくちゃ美味しい！
Mine is 2.5 though. Huh? Eh? Super delicious!
いや、美味しかったんだけど、ベジマイトがいた。
Well, it was delicious, but Vegemite was there.
そうなの、なんか、風邪じゃなかった、ベジマイトが。まだなんか、恋しぐらいあった。まあ確かにそうですね。
That's right, like, it wasn't a cold, but Vegemite was still kinda... longing for it. Well, that's true.
最後、僕のティラミス、ティムタムラミシスですか？
Lastly, my tiramisu, Tim Tam Ramisu?
さん！
Three!
3！
ぼくまさ！やったー！
Boku-masa! Yay!
三つ星すぎ！
Too many three stars!
ベジマイトがティムタムの甘さを生かしてた。ですよね？ うん。
Vegemite brought out the sweetness of the Tim Tam. Right? Yeah.
いや、さすがベジマイトです。もうこのティラミスがもう2つの宝が合わさったことによって、もうたった1つの大秘宝になってた。
Well, as expected of Vegemite. This tiramisu became a single great treasure because those two treasures combined.
あいつオーストラリアから何かもらおうとしてるな。
That guy's trying to get something from Australia.
ぼくアニメ声優やってますからね！ ええ。
I'm doing anime voice acting after all! Heh.
いや、美味しかったこれ。
Man, this was delicious.
企画、まあこういう感じだったんですけど。
The project turned out like this, but
じゃあ、ベジマイトの最初の、まあ……
So, regarding Vegemite, from the start, well...
最初に入れてみてからと
After trying it at first...
感想、まあね、変わりました、もしかして。
your thoughts changed, perhaps?
なんか、物によってはというか、
Well, depending on what it is,
こんなにもやり方次第でベジマイトの味が変化していくものなのかとか、
depending on how it's done, Vegemite's taste can change so much,
なんか色々な使い方があるんだなって意味でびっくりはしたね。
I was surprised at how many different ways there are to use it.
うん、すごくびっくりしました、僕はベジマイト。
Yeah, I was really surprised by Vegemite.
好きになりました？
Did you come to like it?
はい。
Yes.
好きになりました？
Did you come to like it?
はい。
Yes.
好きになりました？
Did you come to like it?
はい。
Yes.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
はい。
Yes.
ベジマイト好きですか？
Do you like Vegemite?
I like Vegemite.
I love Vegemite.
あ、愛します。
Ah, I love it.
Yeah.
はい。
Yes.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
はい。
Yes.
で、ハイズさんは？
And, what about Haiz-san?
俺は、やっぱこう最初の印象はもういろんな味が出ることこう、なんだろ、びっくりするなあ。
For me, my initial impression was like, it has so many flavors, so it's like, surprising.
なんか、みんな食うやん。
Like, everyone eats it.
っていうなんか印象だったんだけど。
That was kind of my impression, but
こんなにいろんな調理の仕方すると、ベジマイトそのいろんな味がするっていういいところをこう、ちょっとずつこう拾っていけるんだと思って。
when you cook it in so many different ways, you can pick up on all the different good flavors of Vegemite bit by bit, I thought.
無限の可能性がある食材だというふうに思いましたね。
I thought it's an ingredient with infinite possibilities.
好きですか？
Do you like it?
好きになりました？
Did you come to like it?
ああ。
Ah...
いや、まあ、ね。
Well, you know...
好きになりました？
Did you come to like it?
あの、あんまり俺、そう。好きになりました？
Well, I don't really... Did you come to like it?
Yes.
え？
Eh?
はい。
Yes.
え？
Eh?
好きになりました？
Did you come to like it?
はい。
Yes.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much!
えっと、みんなもね、気になったらもうぜひぜひベジマイトを自分で作って、自分ですこしね、あの……
Um, everyone, if you're curious, please make Vegemite yourself and enjoy it a bit...
If you experiment with Vegemite, or if you have confidence in your cooking skills...
If you want to find your own ways to find, to enjoy Vegemite, I feel like, you know, it'll, it'll be such a great experience.
瓶はちょっと、瓶はちょっと。
The jar is a bit... The jar is a bit...
まあ、何はともあれべちゃん本当に、あの、マジで、
Well, anyway Bae-chan, really, like, seriously,
マジで5周年おめでとう。ライブ開催もね、おめでとう。
seriously, congratulations on your 5th anniversary. Congratulations on holding the live too.
おめでとう。おめでとう。ありがとうございます。
Congratulations! Congratulations! Thank you very much!
来てくださってありがとうございます。
Thank you for coming.
Thank you to the two for coming, I can't believe this is how I'm celebrating my 5th year anniversary, but I'm so glad it is!
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
ありがとうございます。
じゃあ、せーの！おつベジマイト！
Now then, ready, set! Otsu-Vegemite!
水星！
Suisei!
良い子は真似しないで。
Good kids, don't imitate this!
And with that, we're almost at the end of my anniversary stream! I hope you've had fun today!
いやもう、終わりたくないね。本当に5周年ありがとうございました。
Man, I don't want it to end. Thank you truly so much for the 5th anniversary.
Thank you so much for all the support for five years. We're not done yet!
まだね、お知らせ一個残ってます。なと！
We're still not done! One more announcement remains. And that is...
グッズ出ます！
Merchandise is out!
We still have the last announcement, 5th anniversary merch! We've got some really cool merch this time too. Please check it out!
5th anniversary merch, of course it had to be the Monochrome Dancer and Rat Dancer. This is the Best Oshi merch, this beautiful artwork was done by Hyde-sensei.
えっと、Hyde先生に描いていただきました！今回のグッズのテーマは、まあやっぱり今年発表したモノクロームダンサーの衣装と、えっと、バックダンサーの、まあ2人ですね。はい。
Um, drawn by Hyde-sensei! The theme for this merchandise is, of course, the Monochrome Dancer and outfit we announced this year, and the back dancers, the two of them. Yes.
あの、let's go through each item one by one. First up is this!
Um, let's go through each item one by one. First up is this!
First is the acrylic stand, "Best Oshi" Acrylic Stand. Best Oshi アクリルスタンド ですね。 It's so cool. It features the amazing artwork that Hyde did, and I think it features, it's all the best oshi, my best oshi book desu yo ne, book book desu ne, book book book desu ne, hai, yes, of course, the best oshi, everyone's favorite oshi is me.
First is the acrylic stand, "Best Oshi" Acrylic Stand. Best Oshi acrylic stand. It's so cool. It features the amazing artwork that Hyde did, and I think it features, it's all the best oshi, my best oshi book desu yo ne, book book desu ne, book book book desu ne, hai, yes, of course, the best oshi, everyone's favorite oshi is me.
あ、でも、It does have the two back dancers in the back 'cause I know you guys love them. あ、I'm so obsessed with how it turned out, yeah, めっちゃかっこいい感じになったと思います。
Ah, but, it does have the two back dancers in the back 'cause I know you guys love them. Ah, I'm so obsessed with how it turned out, yeah, I think it turned out looking really cool.
Then next up is this! The Rat Dancer Jacket! Woohoo! やっとですね！Rat Dancerジャケットが、グッズになりました。ジャケットが、いや、本当に素晴らしい。 We've made a few adjustments so it's comfortable and easy to wear in everyday life.
Then next up is this! The Rat Dancer Jacket! Woohoo! Finally! The Rat Dancer Jacket has become merch. The jacket, man, it's really wonderful. We've made a few adjustments so it's comfortable and easy to wear in everyday life.
ちょっとね、あのこのジャケットは着用しやすいようちょっと調整をしたんですけど、本当にかっこいいジャケットになったと思います。
We made a few adjustments so it's easy to wear, but I think it turned out to be a really cool jacket.
What else? Um, this time the 5th anniversary merch, it doesn't involve, it doesn't have as many items just because I know there's a lot happening. We've got the album, you know, and also we've got the live and everything. So it's only these two items, but if you pick up the complete merch set, you'll also get this!
You will get a replica sticker with a signature and an exclusive ASMR voice pack as a special bonus. Thank you so much for always supporting me.
えっと、もしね、今回ちょっとね、あの、色、たくさん告知とかおしらせがあったんですけど、
Um, if, you know, this time, there were a lot of announcements and notices, but...
今回の必須、あの、5周年グッズは2点になります。
The essential items for this 5th anniversary are these two.
えー、もしセット買ってくれてる方に、
Um, for those who bought the set,
ちょっと複製サイン入りのステッカーとASMRボイスが特典で付いてきまーす！
it comes with a duplicated autographed sticker and an ASMR voice pack as a bonus!
The title of the voice pack is "Bae, My Model."
We check out the sample of the red dancer jacket together, and there's even a scene where we recorded using the real jacket sample, so I hope you give it a listen!
えーと、ま、こちらのボイスのタイトルは「ボクのモデルになって」。
Um, well, the title of this voice is "Be My Model."
いや、さっきね、あの、紹介した、え、ジャケットのサンプルを使って、一緒に何かね、あの、ボイスのシチュエーションを作ったっていうか、まあ、あの、収録しました。
Yeah, earlier, you know, using the jacket sample I introduced, we created some kind of voice situation together, well, we recorded it.
お恥ずかしいながら、ぜひ聞いててください。
It's a bit embarrassing, but please be sure to give it a listen.
You can access the shop directly from YouTube, so be sure to check it out!
YouTubeのコラボショップでアクセスできるのでチェックしてくだーさい！はーい！
You can access it via YouTube's collab shop, so please check it out! Hi!
But before I go, there's one more thing I wanted to do with you all. And in order to do that,
I need to first hug... Shien?!
はい、アイドルベイ来ました。
Yes, Idol Bae has arrived.
I just wanted to sing one song before we end today's stream.
I just want to say thank you so much for five years. I'll continue doing my best. Thank you so much for everything you've given me, and I will do my best...
ま、5年間本当にありがとうございました。ちょっと最後にね、1曲歌いたいなと思ってます。
Well, thank you truly so much for the 5 years. I thought I'd like to sing one final song.
気持ちを込めてこれからも頑張りたいと思いますので、最後の1曲聞いてください！
Putting my feelings into it, I want to keep doing my best moving forward, so please listen to this final song!
Music, start!
私のこと知ってますか? 可愛く見えてますか?
Do you know who I am? Do you think I look cute?
私の歌どうだろうな うまく歌えてますか?
What do you think of my singing? Did I manage to sing well?
衣装だとかメイクだとか 可愛く見えてますか?
My outfit and makeup, do I look cute wearing them?
振付とかファンサとかも 喜んでもらえますか?
My dancing and fanservice too, do they make you happy?
手は冷たくなって 足は震える それでも戦いたい アイドルだから
My hands are getting cold and my legs are shaking, but even so, I still want to fight because I'm an idol.
バカにする奴は嫌いだ 見下されるのも嫌いだ
I hate the people who make fun of me, I don't like to be looked down on either.
“アイドルなんか”という言葉を 見てもいないくせに言うな
Don't say words like "idols are nothing" when you haven't even seen them!
頑張りを当然と言うな イメージとか強制するな
Don't take my hard work for granted, don't force an image on me.
“アイドルなんか”という言葉は この世で一番大嫌いだ
Words like "idols are nothing" are the one thing I hate most in this world!
プライベート見えないから 分からないと思います
Because you can't see my private life, I think you don't know.
性格とか悪い方です 騙しちゃってますか?
My personality is actually pretty bad, did I manage to fool you?
でも本気です 本気なんです ありのままの私を 好きになって 推して下さい それってワガママですか?
But it's the truth, I'm being serious. Please love me the way I am and become my fan—is that a selfish thing to ask?
きっと可愛くない 全部分かってる
I'm sure I'm not cute, I already knew it all.
それでも好かれたい アイドルだから
Even so, I still want to be liked because I'm an idol.
皮肉言う奴は嫌いだ 言い訳ばかりも嫌いだ
I hate people who say sarcastic things, I hate people who keep making excuses too.
“こんなもんか”という言葉を 軽々しく口にするな
Don't just say words like "is that all?" so lightly!
勝手に限界決めるな 笑い者になんてするな
Don't just set limits on me, don't make a fool out of me.
“アイドルなんか”という言葉は この世で一番大嫌いだ
Words like "idols are nothing" are the one thing I hate most in this world!
向かい風を切り裂け 誇り高きアイドル
Cutting through the headwinds, a proud idol!
目指そうぜ
Let's aim for it!
応援がなければ 活動できない 好きな事ばかりじゃ 生きてはいけない
Without support I can't do any work, I can't live by doing only what I like.
元気あげるはずが もらってばかりだし 恩返しできる日まで 待ってて 待っててね 12月 約束の…
I'm supposed to give you energy, but I just receive it instead. Until the day I can repay you, wait for me, wait for me! December, our promise...
歓声が減っても 飽きられちゃっても
Even if the cheers fade, even if people grow tired of me,
それでも笑っていたい アイドルだから
still, I want to keep smiling, because I'm an idol.
熱いファンの愛があって
With the passionate love of my fans,
スタッフさんの愛があって
with the love of the staff,
いつも家族の愛があって 生きてる
and always the love of my family, I'm alive—
アイドル！
an idol!
バカにする奴は嫌いだ
I hate people who make fun of us,
見下されるのも嫌いだ
I hate being looked down upon.
“アイドルなんか”という言葉を
Don't casually say words like "just an idol"
見てもいないくせに言うな
when you haven't even watched us!
頑張りを当然と言うな
Don't call our hard work a given.
イメージとか強制するな
Don't force your image on us.
“アイドルなんか”という言葉は
Words like "just an idol"—
この世で一番大嫌いだ
I hate them more than anything in this world!
ありがとうね！
Thank you so much!
MMBB！ MMBB！
MMBB! MMBB!
Thank you everyone for being here!
Don't forget to check out YouTube Music Weekend right after this!
And also give a lot of love to I-Found-Me and ME!
こっからもっと見ててね！
Keep watching me from here on out!
頑張れから！頑張れから！応援して！
Cheer for me! Cheer for me! Support me!
よろしくお願いします！
I'm counting on you!
Thank you so much for five years!
I'll keep doing my best! Bye-bye!
After 5 years... I can finally say... MAMA I MADE IT...